the whole of Europe was buying Everything, just everything that
вся Европа закупала Все просто всё что
was on the market, she was buying everything
на рынке было она всё
Hello Hello, I’m from Khmelnitsky
Здравствуйте Привет я из Хмельницкого Вы
Where are you from? I’m from the city of St. Petersburg, I
откуда Я из города санкт-петербурга
understand, look, I’m asking people from Russia
понял смотрите Я у людей из России
how you see the end of yours
спрашиваю как вы видите окончание сво
And I think that it’s
А я считаю что
necessary Well, to go as far as possible  then
нужно Ну максимально идти на какие-то
concessions from all sides, that is, to
уступки э со всех сторон то есть
come to the
приходить Ну к
maximum agreement in the sense
максимальному согласию в том плане то
that those sacrifices that exist on one
что вот те жертвы которые есть с одной и
side and on the other are Well, it’s [ __ ] up, it’s
с другой стороны это Ну [__] это
just [ __ ] up, no. So who should make
просто [__] нет Так кто должен пойти
these
на эти
concessions? I think the whole world should make these
уступки Я думаю весь мир должен на эти
make all the concessions because the
все уступки пойти потому что в этом
whole world is already involved in this Well, as it were, what
замешан уже весь мир Ну как бы а в чём в
should be the concessions? What are the demands of the
чём должны быть уступки Какие требования
parties to give, here are the demands of Ukraine
сторон давать вот требования Украины
to return to the Borders of 9, that is, to
вернуться на Границы 9 года то есть
return control over Lugansk Crimea
возвратить контроль над Луганском Крымом
Donetsk and all territories And what are the
Донецком и всеми территориями А какие
demands of
требования
Russia Listen  I don’t know what the requirements are,
России Слушай я не знаю какие требования
but at least that’s what, well, I’m not speaking
но по крайней мере то что ну я не говорю
for any official position there, but I
там за какую-то официальную позицию но я
assume that this is the line of
так предполагаю то что вот та линия
demarcation that
разграничения которая
exists, it’s possible, it’s possible, but it seems to me that
есть возможно возможно но мне кажется то
this is Yes, if something like this is the case, it
это Да если вот примерно так ВС это
will end  It seems to me that this won’t really
закончится Мне кажется это не ну реально
stop some kind of I don’t know
остановит какую-то там я не знаю
the opposing sides there from,
противоборствующие сторону там со
let’s say, Russia or from
стороны допустим России или со стороны
Ukraine in the sense that there is the Dnieper,
Украины в том плане то что есть Днепр да
yes, that is, many people say that there is a
то есть многие говорят то что вот
border along the
граница по
Dnieper, sort of, yes, I understand  the fact that there
Днепру как бы да типа я понимаю то что
is full sovereignty of Ukraine there,
есть там суверенитет Украины в полной
that is, Ukraine can still
мере то есть Украина дож
exist there, as it were, the fact that I live in
существовать как бы там то что я живу в
Russia Well, it’s difficult for me
России Ну мне сложно как-то об этом
to talk about it somehow, that is, where is where there is a
говорить то есть где вот где там
truthful point where both sides will
Правдивая точка где обоим сторонам будет
understand, but I understand perfectly well  that
понятно но я прекрасно понимаю то что у
I have a very, very large bunch of real
меня очень ну большая куча реально
acquaintances who
знакомых которые
died and you 100% have acquaintances
погибли и у вас 100% есть знакомые
who died,
которые погибли
so the difficult question is actually in the
поэтому сложный вопрос на самом деле в
World Cup. I can’t understand when, if we
ЧМ Я не могу понять вот когда если мы
bargain, yes, Ukraine was Ukraine,
торгуемся да Украина вот была Украина
Russia climbed into the territory of Ukraine and
Россия залезла на территорию Украины и
now says  Let's make concessions in that
теперь говорит Давайте уступки в том что
you will give us where we stand, what's the
вы нам отдадите где мы стоим в чём
joke? Well, no, well, history is written by
прикол Ну нет ну историю пишут
the victors. I think you're very familiar with this,
победители Я думаю ты прекрасно с этим
and well, given the fact that
знаком и ну учитывая то что
now, in general, Ukraine is leaving. In defense,
сейчас в целом Украина уходит В защиту
the President of Ukraine himself said this,
сам президент Украины об этом сказал
so now the closest Counter there  there
поэтому сейчас ближайших там Контр
won’t be any offensives or as they call them counterattacks, it’s 100% so
контрнаступ их не будет это 100% поэтому
uh I think that given that
э Я думаю то что учитывая что снижается
support for Ukraine from all over the West is declining, it’s
поддержка Украины со всего Запада то
more logical to assume that now
логичнее предположить то что сейчас как
it seems to have a leading role on the side of Russia,
бы лидирующая роль она на стороне России
so Russia will
поэтому Росси
take it on its own terms You burn Russia one and
на своих условиях вать Ты гори Россия
a half  years ago it stood almost near
полтора года назад стояла почти под
Kiev, it could
Киевом она могла
dictate Since then, Russia was expelled from
диктовать С тех пор Россию выгнали с с
Kiev from the Sumy region from Chernigov from
Киева с Сумской области с Черниговской с
Zhitomir from Kharkov from Kherson from the
Житомирской с Харьковской с Херсона с
Nikolaev
Николаевской
region and do you think that now Russia
области и ты считаешь что сейчас Россия
can now dictate after a year and a half of
Теперь может диктовать после полтора
retreats, of course economic growth is
отступлений конечно рост экономики
3.5  This is more than all European
3,5 Это больше чем у всех европейских
powers; economic growth is 35%;
держав у ковой рост экономики 35% у
Russia has what in Russia; Ukraine has minus 42
России какой в России у Украины мину 42
if Russia's GDP is
если ВП России
what Russia's GDP is almost
какой ВВП России - это почти
3.2% of the world's
3,2% мирового
GDP; look, let's do the same. You compare the GDP of
ВП смотри давай так е Ты сравнишь ВВП
Russia and the GDP of the USA in How much?  since Russia
России и ВВП США в Сколько раз у России
has less here it’s not measured like that
меньше здесь это так не измеряется
measured
измеряется
in people there is no GDP just in dollars or in
в людя нет ВВП как раз в долларах или в
dollars per capita if gdp what’s
долларах на душу населения если gdp
the use of how much population does the
прока сколько населения
USA have look the USA will win
у США смотри США выиграет у России
a lot over Russia and according to gdp per Kata and in general
сильно и по gdp per Ката и по общему
I want right now and how much  population
хоче сечас пря а сколько населения
more than 3 how many centuries does Russia need to
больше 3 сколько столетий России нужно
increase the economy by 3% to catch up with
повышать экономику на 3% чтобы догнать
modern America here I agree with you
современную Америку здесь я с тобой
that this is difficult to do
согласен то что это Это сложно сделать
considering that we have the main problem
учитывая что у нас есть главная проблема
- a lack of people, that’s all, that is,
- это нехватка людей вот и всё то есть
this is the main problem but at the same time  the
вот это главная проблема но при этом
economy is growing, it is growing at a fairly
экономика растёт она растёт достаточно
good pace, so it’s kind of
хорошими темпами поэтому как бы о том
interesting that at the beginning of the year, it’s interesting. Okay, but I can’t. I’m
интересно Хорошо можно вот я не могу Я
not really an economist. You can understand
не совсем экономист можно понять за счёт
why the economy is growing if Russia spends a
чего растёт экономика если Россия тратит
huge amount of money on war and
огромнейшее количество денег на войну
just bury it in the ground  Yes, they
просто закапывает в землю Да у России
began to buy less energy from Russia Yes,
меньше стали покупать энергоносителей Да
due to which the economy is growing What that
за счёт чего растёт экономика Что что
Russia began to sell new things to the world
Россия начала новое продавать в мир А
But the most interesting thing is that Russia did
вот самое интересное то что россия-то
not begin to sell less,
она не стала продавать меньше она стала
on the contrary, it began to sell more And at the same time
продавать наоборот больше И при этом
earning from energy resources A little
зарабатывая от энергоносителей Немного
more, see  It turns out that we are in the same place. So, come
больше смотри у нас получается жеде мо
on, you can show me where you
Вот давай так можешь мне показать где от
started to earn more from energy sources,
энергоносителей стало зарабатывать
show the stars now, well, I’m unlikely to
звезд показать сейчас ну я тут те вряд
be able to do it anywhere, but I can
ли где-то смогу но я те могу с словами
explain it in words, look at what’s very good during this time, and
объяснить смотри то что за это время
whether to buy at discounted prices  a huge amount of
ли покупать огромное количество
Enem than you transport to India China
Энем чем вы транспортиру в Индию Китай
a huge amount Well, I saw the information
огромное количество Ну видел информацию
that 200 somewhere 50 tankers Nena was for
что 200 где-то 50 танкеров нены было за
what 250 tankers Well this is
что такое 250 танкеров Ну
where where are they That is, you now, that is, it
это где где они То есть вы сейчас то
turns out sri Previously, you had a
есть получается сри Раньше у вас был
gas pipeline to Europe there A  Now you are
газопровод в Европу там А сейчас вы
somewhere carrying a tanker across the Arctic
где-то танкера через Северный Ледовитый
Ocean,
океан чтото
250 tankers have been purchased, that is, there is
возите закуплено 250 танкеров то есть
also some kind of shadow fleet, of course
ещё какой-то теневой флот он естественно
there is and look at the data as of December 1,
имеется и смотри данные на 1 декабря
2023, the income of the largest
2023 года доходы крупнейших
oil and gas producers in the Russian Federation fell
производителей нефти и газа в РФ упали
by 41, about this by 20  January 1,
на 41 про это на 20 на 1 января 2023
2023 December 1, December here is the latest
года 1 декабря декабря вот свежая
news 902 published so the income of
новость 902 опубликовано так доходы ших
Russian oil and
российских производителей нефти и
natural gas producers fell by 41 in the first 9
природного газа упали на 41 за первые 9
months of this year Damir yes,
месяцев этого года дамире да об этом
the Central Bank reported this in its review of
сообщил Центробанк в своём обзоре
financial stability since the volume of
финансовой стабильности поскольку обём
exports since export volumes and
экспорта поскольку объёмы экспорта и
prices
цены
have decreased  of course, damn it, considering the
снизились конечно ну блин учитывая
record-breaking twenty-second year when the whole of
рекордный двадцать второй год когда вся
Europe was buying Everything, it’s just everything that
Европа закупала Все просто всё что на
was on the market, she bought everything again and
рынке было она всё закупала е раз ещё
again like that No,
раз так Нет
calm down, I showed you
давай спокойнее я тебе показал
specific data, you’re saying that you have a
конкретные данные ты говоришь что у вас
war going on, your trade chains are breaking,
идёт Война у вас э рвутся торговые
yeah  you are being imposed sanctions
цепочки Да на вас накладывают санкции
no look And you say that your
нет смотри И ты говоришь что у вас
sales have increased I’m telling you why the
выросли продажи Я же говорю за счёт чего
official one is falling and your
вот официальная да у вас падает и объём
sales volume and sales prices are falling Yes due to
продаж и цены продаж падают Да за счёт
what your sales are growing Well,
чего у вас вырастает
at least because of the price of oil
Ну как По крайней мере из-за цены нефти
in  in the twenty-second year the price was lower,
в двадцать втором году цена была ниже
look again It increased, not I say, not I
смотри ещё раз Выросла не я говорю не я
say But your center gang about their review of
говорю А ваша центр банда о своём обзоре
financial stability since
финансовой стабильности поскольку объёмы
export volumes and prices decreased, that is, the
экспорта и цены снизились то есть объём
sales volume you began to sell less and you
продаж вы стали продавать меньше и вы
began to sell cheaper, where did the increase
стали продавать дешевле откуда повышение
begin to sell
стали продавать
more we  they started selling more no
больше мы стали продавать больше нет
Show find find news Where do you
Покажи найди найди новость Где вы
sell more Find No I’m just
продаёте больше Найди Нет я тебе просто
telling you what look how it’s dest no
говорю то что смотри как это дест нет
look Your news says that they started
смотри Ваши новости говорят что стали
selling less I deliberately thought
продавать меньше я специально я думал
maybe I No I agree I no no I
может я Нет я согласен я нет нет я
agree they started selling less  But
согласен стали продавать меньше Но у нас
other economies have begun to grow in our country, so
стали расти другие
with oil you
экономики то с нефтью значит по нефти вы
have sank in terms of oil. Well, as they say, I don’t know there.
просели Ну как говорит я не знаю там
Any person in our country as a whole is now
Любой человек у нас в целом сейчас
developing, I don’t think you’re talking about what we
развивается поди про не ты то что мы
just got to and you agreed that they
только что дошли и ты согласился что
began to sell less oil and the price
нефти стали продавать меньше и цена
less everything in terms of oil you are in the street there is no price
меньше всё по нефти вы в ули нет цена
price now lately it is
цена сейчас в последнее время она она
once again
ещё раз
seen in terms of price you with the pre-war this you are
смот по цене вы с довоенным этим вы
losing Yes and in terms of everything in terms of oil
проигрываете Да и по обём всё по нефти
income in general income you have
доходы в общем доходы у вас вот есть
official data fell by 41 about almost
официальные данные упали на 41 про почти
twice So where did you
в два раза Так а где вы
go up? Well, they went up, it’s the
поднялись Ну поднялись это
manufacturing industry, it
обрабатывающая промышленность она
really
действительно
demonstrated yes. We
продемонстрировала да Всё мы
process everything and in general then Well, [ __ ], I don’t
обрабатываем и в целом то Ну [__] я не
know there so that I look, for example, what’s
знаю там чтобы я посмотрел например что
in the image. I looked at how to
в обра Я посмотрел как
export. Yes, if you have access there.
экспорт Да у тебя если есть там доступ
Yes, so that I  I knew that googling there
Да чтобы я знал что гуглить там
cars you export or
автомобили Вы экспортирует или
that to the whole world Sorry for the swearing
что во весь мир Извините за матюка
they export the letter to my Telegram directly at the same
экспортируют пись на мий Telegram прямо
time axis VN and
зараз ось ВН а
Popik is more and more
Попик це дуже и дуже
polite yes
важливо да